# NATE SCHIER

601 E 2nd St., Apt. 324, Los Angeles CA 90012 808-294-5948 ◆ nathaniel.schier@gmail.com nateschier.com ◆ linkedin.com/in/nateschier ◆ github.com/cosst

#### SUMMARY

After co-founding and growing Sidebench for 5 years (#329 on the Inc. 500 list for 2017), I decided to leave the company in July 2017 to fulfill a long time desire to build my own software engineering skillset. Currently interested in contract work, apprenticeships, and potentially full-time positions with a high-performing team where I can both contribute and learn.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Full Stack JavaScript Engineer

Los Angeles, CA

Contract & Self-Study

September 2017 - Present

- Focus primarily on full-stack JavaScript and more specifically React & Node
- Learn through a mix of contract work, my own projects, tutorials, online reading, and contributing to open source
- Completed Harvard's CS50x to build foundational CS knowledge
- GitHub profile: https://github.com/cosst
- <u>Technologies</u>: JavaScript, React, Node, React Native, Vue, Python, Express, MongoDB, RethinkDB, REST APIs, Mocha, Chai, webpack, Babel, Git, Yarn/npm, Heroku, Firebase

Sidebench Los Angeles, CA

Co-Founder & Director

April 2012 - July 2017

- Co-founded a leading LA-based product consulting company; bootstrapped it to \$2.5m revenue in 2016
- Ranked #329 on the 2017 Inc. 500 list with 3-year growth of 1346%
- Responsible for *everything* early on; as company grew I focused primarily on internal operations, hiring & retention, and high-level account management along with some sales
- Grew company from a group of remote contractors in 2012 to an in-house team of 20 employees in 2017; served as hiring manager across design, product, and engineering teams
- Helped clients identify, design, develop, and launch strategic technology solutions; clients included Red Bull, Oakley, Andreessen Horowitz, NBC Universal, Inland Empire Health Plan, and Sony
- Awards:
  - o Top 5 Enterprise App & Web Developers in America (Clutch)
  - o Top 5 Mobile App Developers in Los Angeles (SourcingLine)
  - o Most Promising Enterprise Mobility Solution Providers (CIO Review Magazine)
  - o 2017 Social Impact App nOCD (Mobile UX Awards)
  - Left company voluntarily in July 2017 to build personal software engineering skillset

# Elm Talent Group

New Haven, CT

Recruiting Associate & First Employee

August 2011 - September 2013

- Connected intelligent early-career talent with elite retained clients in the finance, tech, and life science sectors Responsible for client and candidate management, sourcing, screening, and closure; personally placed 25+
- candidates at Bridgewater Associates, one of the most selective buy-side institutions in the New York area
- As the first employee, helped name, brand, and build the company; implemented structure and training procedures in order to successfully onboard new Recruiting Associates

Hawaii Literacy Honolulu, HI

ESL Center Director

June 2010 - May 2011

• Managed and taught at English literacy non-profit; promoted from volunteer to lead teacher to director over the course of three months; provided free ESL instruction for ~250 students a year; grew center by 100% in one year

## **EDUCATION**

Pomona College
B.A. English

May 2010

- **Extracurricular Activities**: Rugby (2010 D2 National Champions), Varsity Football, ITS Helpdesk
- Honors: Pomona College Scholar, National Football Foundation Hampshire Honor Society
- **Study Abroad**: Beijing (Summer 2008), Edinburgh (Fall 2008)

### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

**Skills**: Google-fu, scrappiness, listening, leadership, empathy, pattern recognition, recruiting, team building, dog whispering **Interests**: my dog Daphne, NYT Crosswords, downtown LA, Mad Men, topographical maps, NY-style pizza, rugby, Hawaii